Rishi Raj Dutta

33 Iroquois Street, Boston, MA 02120 617.921.8279 rishiraj.dutta3@yahoo.com

www.linkedin.com/in/rishirajdutta/

Summary

Software Engineer with experience in e-commerce and product market analysis; have developed e-commerce application in multiple frameworks, knowledge of software development lifecycle, requirement gathering and remodeling with agile methodology; performed presentation delivery, event management and marketing and sales of product curriculum. Interested in developing client business focused applications

Technical Skills

Programming Languages: C, C++, Java, Python

Web Technologies: CSS, HTML5, JavaScript, XQuery

Databases: MySQL, MS SQL Server, Oracle 11g, PostgreSQL Talend Studio for Data Integration, SSIS, TOAD Data Integration Tools: **Data Visualization Tools:** Tableau, Qlik Sense, PowerBI, MS Excel Frameworks: Eclipse, EditiX, NetBeans, gedit, Swing

Operating Systems: Windows, Fedora, Ubuntu, Mac OS

Education

Northeastern University, Boston, MA, USA

Master of Science in Information Systems

Relevant Courses: Application Engineering & Development, Advances in Data Science and Architecture, Business Intelligence & Data Warehousing

Pune University, Pune, MH, India

Jun 2016

Bachelor of Engineering in Information Technology

Work Experience

Event Coordinator (Intern)

FC Pune City, Pune, MH, India

Oct 2015 - Nov 2015

An Indian professional soccer franchise based in the city of Pune which plays in the Major League of India known as Indian Super League

- Scouted soccer players between the age demographics of 12 to 17 years for boys and girls under national level grassroot development program
- Implemented a fixture schedule following round robin algorithm with the use of seeding and bye
- Maintained a coherent excel data model of 62 fixtures and created profiles of 260 players using data sheets for records
- Displayed social motor skills by coordination is a multi-team environment which led to time organized matches of 30 minutes each half.
- Understood the functioning of the various levels of committees and their respective responsibilities in the management of the soccer franchise

Marketing & Sales Analyst (Intern)

Sportal Corporate PVT LTD, Pune, MH, India

Dec 2014- Feb 2015

A private physical education company whose goal is to develop a unique corporate sporting culture where every Sports Event is customized to the client needs and the work domain ranges from kindergarten to corporate level

- Delivered multiple presentations and learned to negotiate business with potential clients
- Maintained and tracked the data of 58 schools in excel spreadsheets for statistical analysis
- Learned the implementation of pitching sales target on client base
- Studied new trends in client market base upon history analysis for example companies with 65% of employees more than 35 years of age are less prone to participate in corporate sporting events.

Academic Projects

Pune University, Pune, MH, India

E-commerce Product Rating System

Feb 2016 - May 2016

- Designed an e-commerce website for purchasing of commercial products using JavaScript
- Provided a statistical 10 scale rating model of the product intrinsic to its characteristic and functionality
- Objective was to help customers in making a better and optimal purchase decision by an accuracy of 25%
- Analyzed data by mining the large set of customer feedback comments into structured natural language processing algorithms to assign weights to clusters of features in a product

May 2019